Piers Anthony Papers
Piers Anthony Papers
1951-1978
Anthony, Piers.
16 linear ft.
Papers of the British American author, science fiction and fantasy novelist. Born Piers Anthony Dillingham Jacob in England in 1934. Includes correspondence with editors, fans, and other authors (1960-1969); and writings, including typescript draft and manuscript short stories and novels. Correspondents of interest include Poul Andersen, Isaac Asimov, Lloyd Biggle, Terry Carr, Robert Coulson, Samuel R. Delany, Anne McCaffrey, Robert Margroff, Andre Norton, Andrew J. Offutt, Alexei Panshin, Frederik Pohl, Norman Spinrad, and Roger Zelazny.
148816
Biographical History
Piers Anthony (born Piers Anthony Dillingham Jacob in Oxford, England, in 1934) is an American novelist. Anthony's family came to the United States when he was four years old; he graduated from Goddard College in Vermont, served in the United States Army (1957-1959), and became a citizen in his twenties. While in the army he was editor and cartoonist for the battalion newspaper, and in the early 1960s he turned to writing full-time. He is one of the most prolific science fiction and fantasy authors with numerous best-sellers to his credit along with almost a dozen Hugo and Nebula Award nominations. In addition to dozens of science fiction and fantasy novels, he has written historical fiction, martial arts, and horror.
He is best know for his seven-volume Incarnations of Immortality and for the long-running Xanth series which has more than thirty titles, most of which are puns (e.g. Faun and Games, Swell Foop, Roc and a Hard Place, Stork Naked). He has been nominated for numerous Hugo and Nebula Awards.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Piers Anthony Papers consists of correspondence, writings and memorabilia.
Correspondence is arranged alphabetically by correspondent, with the exception of Editors and publishers and Fans, which are filed at the end. Notable correspondents include Poul Anderson, Isaac Asimov, Lloyd Biggle Jr., Nathan A. Bucklin, Robert Coulson, Harlan Ellison, Roberto Fuentes, Richard Geis, Ron Goodman, Joseph L. Green, Margie Harrison, H. James Hotaling, Seth A. Johnson, Robert E. Margroff, Larry Pinsker, Andrew J. Offutt, Frederick Pohl, Norman Spinrad, Robert Moore Williams and Roger Zelazny. Around 1962 Piers Anthony joined a science fiction fan club called the National Fantasy Fan Federation (N3F); much of the correspondence in the collection was generated through this connection, most of it involving critical dialogues concerning specific works, often among two or more of the correspondents. Included in this category would be the Neffer Robin letters.
Writings includes works by Anthony alone, collaborative works, and a few works by others. Types of material include articles, books, poetry, short stories, and several then-unpublished novels that have since been published. Among the major works represented are Chthon (1967), Hasan (1970), Macroscope (1969), Omnivore (1968), Sos the Rope (1968), and Var the Stick (1969). There are also drafts of collaborations by Piers Anthony with Frances Hall, H. James Hotaling, Robert Margroff (The E. S. P. Worm), Roberto Fuentes (the Jason Striker series, also known as "the Ninja books" or "the judo books"), Andrew Offutt, and Richard Tiedman.
Memorabilia includes material related to Goddard College, and several of Anthony's personal journals.
Arrangement of the Collection
Material is arranged alphabetically by type, title or name.
Related Material
has a number of collections relating to science fiction. Please refer to for a complete listing.
Separated Material
The collection originally contained published editions of a number of Anthony's novels. These have been transferred to Rare Books for cataloging. Please refer to to locate these itemanuscript
Subject and Genre Headings
Literature -- American Fiction; Science fiction; Andersen, Poul.; Anthony, Piers.; Asimov, Isaac, 1920-1992.; Biggle, Lloyd, Jr., 1923-2002.; Carr, Terry.; Coulson, Robert, 1928-1999.; Delany, Samuel R.; Ellison, Harlan.; Fuentes, Roberto, 1934-; Gerrold, David, 1944-; McCaffrey, Anne.; Margroff, Robert E., 1930-; Norton, Andre.; Offutt, Andrew J.; Panshin, Alexei, 1940-; Pohl, Frederik.; Spinrad, Norman.; Zelazny, Roger.; American literature -- 20th century.; Authors, American.; British Americans.; Fantasy literature, American.; Novelists, American.; Science fiction, American.; Articles.; Correspondence.; Diaries.; Poetry.; Manuscripts for publication.; Authors.; Novelists.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Material in boxes 10 and 19 is restricted and may not be viewed without Mr. Anthony's written permission
Acquisition Information
Gift of Piers Anthony, 1969, 1970, 1978.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - Family, 1951-1969; 4 folders (Box 19)
    Requires written permission of Mr. Anthony to view.
  - Index, 1963 (Box 1)
  - Anderson, Poul, 1966-1967 (Box 1)
  - Asimov, Isaac, 1961 (Box 1)
  - A, 1961-1967 (Box 1)
  - Biggle, Lloyd Jr., 1961-1968 (Box 1)
  - Bodkin, Ronald, 1960-1968 (Box 1)
  - Bucklin, Nathan A., 1963-1965 (Box 1)
  - Burger, Joanne, 1968-1969 (Box 1)
  - B, 1961-1968 (Box 1)
  - Carr, Terry, 1967-1969 (Box 1)
  - Coulson, Robert and Juanita, 1963-1969 (Box 1)
  - C, 1960-1967, 1969 (Box 1)
  - Delany, Samuel R., 1966-1967 (Box 1)
  - The Demise, correspondence related to the short story (Box 1)
  - D, 1952-1967 (Box 1)
  - Ellison, Harlan, 1968 (Box 1)
  - E, 1961-1962; 1967, 1969 (Box 1)
  - Fuentes, Roberto, 1970 (Box 1)
  - Fuentes, Roberto, 1970-1973 (Box 2)
  - F, 1961-1963; 1967,; 1969 (Box 2)
  - Galouye, Dan, 1969 (Box 2)
  - Geis, Richard, 1968-1969 (Box 2)
  - Goodman, Ron, 1963-1965 (Box 2)
  - Green, Joseph L., 1967-1969 (Box 2)
  - G, 1958-1968 (Box 2)
  - Hall, Francis T., 1963-1969 (Box 19)
  - Hill, Alma, 1962-1969 (Box 19)
  - Harrison, Margie, 1963-1966 (Box 2)
  - Hoffmeister, Robert, 1966-1968 (Box 2)
  - Hotaling, H. James, 1962-1967 (Box 2)
  - H, 1961-1965 (Box 2)
  - I, 1961-1967 (Box 2)
  - Johnson, Seth A., 1962-1969 (Box 3)
  - K, 1962-1967 (Box 3)
  - Lunney, Frank, 1968-1969 (Box 3)
  - L, 1961-1968 (Box 3)
  - Margroff, Robert E., 1963-1969; 4 folders (Box 3)
  - McCaffrey, Anne, 1967-1968 (Box 3)
  - M, 1955-1969 (Box 3)
  - Neffer Robin #146, 1963-1964 (Box 4)
  - Neffer Robin #149, 1963-1964 (Box 4)
  - Neffer Robin #152, 1963 (Box 4)
  - Norton, Andre, 1967-1969 (Box 4)
  - N, 1964-1967 (Box 4)
  - Offutt, Andrew J., 1963-1969; 3 folders (Box 4)
  - O, 1964 (Box 4)
  - Panshin, Alexei, 1968-1969 (Box 4)
  - Pinsker, Larry, 1963-1965 (Box 4)
  - Pohl, Frederick, 1965-1969 (Box 4)
  - "Pro/2", 1963-1965; 2 folders (Box 19)
  - P, 1961-1969 (Box 4)
  - Q, 1963 (Box 4)
  - R, 1954-1968 (Box 4)
  - Spinrad, Norman, 1967-1968 (Box 5)
  - S, 1952-1968 (Box 5)
  - Tiedman, Richard, 1962-1967; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - T, 1962-1963 (Box 5)
  - Uzzell, Thomas H. and Amelia W., 1961-1962; material for course entitled "Fundamentals of Fiction", the Uzzell Course (Box 5)
  - U, V, 1962-1965 (Box 5)
  - Williams, Robert Moore, 1968-1969 (Box 5)
  - W, 1952-1963 (Box 5)
  - Zelazny, Roger, 1966 (Box 5)
  - Y, Z, 1961-1967 (Box 5)
  - Editors and publishers, 1958-1968; 6 folders (Box 5)
  - Editors and Publishers, 1963-1969; undated; 3 folders (Box 6)
  - Fans, 1963-1969; undated; 4 folders (Box 6)
  - Unidentified, 1955-1968 (Box 6)
  - Originals of items photocopied for preservation (Box 6)
- Writings
  - Articles and essays
    - Alf Laylah Wa Laylah, drafts; 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Bastille, autobiographic article on student teaching; typescript manuscript, correspondence, and notes about pranks (Box 6)
    - Hop, Skip, and Jump School, Family Academic Services Center; holograph and typescript manuscript, research materials (Box 6)
    - The Surgeon Who Also Walks Dogs, veterinary medicine; holograph and typescript manuscript, research materials (Box 6)
    - Telephone, holograph and typescript manuscript, research material (Box 6)
    - Miscellaneous, 1969 (Box 7)
  - Books
    - Black Castle of the Amazon (with Roberto Fuentes), 3 folders (Box 7)
      This material includes notes and correspondence with Roberto Fuentes, draft holograph manuscript, typescript manuscript, and completed typescript manuscript. Although notated as "Jason Striker/5", this seems to be #3 in the Jason Striker series of books that was published, entitled "Amazon Slaughter - The Curse of the Ninja"
    - But What of Earth? (with Robert Coulson), 1st and 2nd draft typescript and holograph manuscript (Box 7)
    - Chaining the Lady
      - 1st draft, holograph manuscript (Box 7)
      - 2nd draft, typescript manuscript (Box 8)
    - Chthon
      - Notes, revised manuscript, holograph and typescript (Box 8)
      - Draft A [title: "The Minionette"], holograph and revised typescript manuscript (Box 8)
      - Draft B, revised typescript (Box 8)
      - Draft C [title: The Broken Song], mimeographed typescript (Box 8)
      - Draft D, chapter and outline, 2nd draft (Box 8)
      - Draft E, 2 revised typescripts (Box 8)
      - Draft E, typescript (Box 8)
      - Draft F, printer's copy, revised typescript (pp. 1-143) (Box 8)
      - Draft F, printer's copy, revised typescript (pp. 144-300) (Box 9)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 9)
      - Chthon, Ballantine: New York, 1967, This item has been sent to Rare Books for cataloging. Please refer to to locate this item.
      - Chthon, Macdonald & Co.: London, 1970, This item has been sent to Rare Books for cataloging. Please refer to to locate this item.
    - Cluster, holograph and typescript manuscript; 4 folders (Box 9)
    - Dead Morn (with Roberto Fuentes), pencil drafts and typescript manuscript; 2 folders (Box 9)
    - The E. S. P. Worm (with Robert E. Margroff), 1968-1969; drafts; 5 folders (Box 11)
    - Ghost, adaptation from novelette; holograph and typescript manuscript (Box 11)
    - Hasan
      - Notes (Box 11)
      - Draft A, revised typescript ms (Box 11)
      - Draft B, holograph ms (Box 11)
      - Draft C, revised typescript ms (Box 11)
      - Draft D, typescript ms (Box 12)
      - Draft E, typescript manuscript; 2 folders (Box 12)
      - Fantastic Stories, v. 19, containing story printed as serial, 1966-1970 (Box 12)
      - Published material: Hasan, Borgo Press: San Bernardino, 1977, This item has been sent to Rare Books for cataloging. Please refer to to locate this item.
    - Kiai! (with Roberto Fuentes), 1 holograph and 3 typescript manuscripts; 4 folders (Box 12)
    - Kirlian Quest, 2nd draft; holograph and typescript manuscript; 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Macroscope
      - Notes (Box 13)
      - Draft A, holograph manuscript; 2 folders (Box 13)
      - Draft B, typescript, revised holograph; 3 folders (Box 13)
      - Draft C [copy 1], reproduction, revised; 4 folders (Box 14)
      - Draft C [copy 2, pp. 1-274), reproduction, revised; 2 folders (Box 14)
      - Draft C [copy 2, pp. 275-694], reproduction, revised; 2 folders (Box 15)
      - Page proofs, incomplete (Box 15)
      - Marked copy, revisions for the British edition (Box 15)
      - Miscellaneous, notes and related correspondence (Box 15)
    - Mandroid (with Robert E. Margroff and Andrew Offutt), draft; 2 folders (Box 15)
    - Mer-cycle
      - Research notes and materials (Box 15)
      - 2nd draft, typescript manuscript (Box 15)
    - Mistress of Death (with Roberto Fuentes) [working title: Kill-13], typescript manuscript; 2 folders (Box 16)
    - Neq the Sword, notes, original holograph, "2nd draft" typescript manuscript, typescript manuscript; 4 folders (Box 16)
    - Ninja (with Roberto Fuentes)
      All of this material includes extensive back-and-forth with Roberto Fuentes about the upcoming Ninja series he and Anthony were working on, which eventually became the 6-part "Jason Striker Martial Art Series" novels/. It is unclear if this manuscript was published or not as is, but most likely it became one of the volumes in the Ninja series.
      - "2nd draft", holograph and typescript, with notes and correspondence with Roberto Fuentes (Box 16)
      - "2nd draft", holograph and typescript, with notes and correspondence with Roberto Fuentes (Box 17)
      - [Unidentified draft], typescript ms (Box 17)
    - Ninja's Revenge (with Roberto Fuentes) [working title: Tao!], holograph and typescript manuscript; also includes working notes and correspondence between Anthony and Fuentes; 2 folders (Box 17)
    - Omnivore
      - Notes, holograph text (Box 17)
      - Draft A, holograph ms (Box 17)
      - Draft B, typescript ms (Box 17)
      - Draft C, 2nd draft (Box 17)
      - Draft D, third version, second draft (Box 17)
      - Draft E, version #3 (Box 17)
      - Draft F, typescript ms (Box 17)
      - Draft G, typescript ms (Box 18)
      - Draft H, typescript ms (Box 18)
      - Draft I, typescript ms (Box 18)
      - Book reviews from Publisher's Weekly, Nov. 11, 1968 (Box 18)
      - Published material: Omnivore, Ballantine: New York, 1968, This item has been sent to Rare Books for cataloging. Please refer to to locate this item.
      - Published material: Omnivore, Faber & Faber, London, 1969, This item has been sent to Rare Books for cataloging. Please refer to to locate this item.
    - Orn [working title: Paleo]
      - Draft, holograph ms (Box 18)
      - "second draft", typescript manuscript (Box 18)
      - "Setting copy", typescript manuscript; 2 folders (Box 18)
      - Galley proof (Box 21)
      - Published material: Amazing Stories, v. 44, no. 2-3, July-Sept. 1970 (Box 21)
    - Ox, holograph, 2nd draft, and typescript manuscript; 4 folders (Box 21)
    - Phthor
      - 1st and 2nd drafts, research notes, holograph and typescript manuscript; 2 folders (Box 22)
      - "2nd draft, remainder of novel" (Box 22)
    - A Piece of Cake, notes, drafts; 9 folders (Box 22)
    - Pornucopia
      - 1st draft, holograph manuscript (Box 22)
      - 2nd draft, typescript manuscript (Box 22)
    - The Pretender (with Frances Hall), notes, drafts, "revision working copy," typescript manuscript; 6 folders (Box 23)
    - Race Against Time, juvenile novel
      - "1st draft", holograph manuscript (Box 23)
      - 2nd draft "revision", typescript manuscript (Box 23)
      - [Unidentified draft], holograph and typescript manuscript; 2 folders (Box 23)
    - The Ring, 1968; undated
      - Notes and holograph manuscript (Box 23)
      - Draft A, typescript ms (Box 23)
      - Draft B, holograph ms (Box 23)
      - Draft C, 2nd draft edition typescript ms (Box 24)
      - Draft D, marked copy, revisions from 1st submission version to final version typescript manuscript; 3 folders (Box 24)
      - Draft E, printer's copy typescript manuscript, pp. 1-290; 3 folders (Box 24)
      - Published material: The Ring, Ace Books, 1968; This item has been sent to Rare Books for cataloging. Please refer to to locate this item.
    - Rings of Ice (with terminal essay by Donald L. Cyr), typescript manuscript (Box 24)
    - Sos the Rope, 1967; 1968,; undated
      - Notes (Box 24)
      - Draft A, holograph ms (Box 24)
      - Draft B, 2nd draft typescript ms (Box 25)
      - Draft C, typescript manuscript; 2 folders (Box 25)
      - Draft D, printer's copy typescript manuscript; 2 folders (Box 25)
      - Draft D [copy 2], printer's copy typescript manuscript; 2 folders (Box 25)
      - Published material: The Magazine of Fantasy and Science Fiction, v. 35, no's 1, 2, 3, 1968 (Box 25)
      - Published material: Sos the Rope, Pyramid Books, NY, 1968, This item has been sent to Rare Books for cataloging. Please refer to to locate this item.
      - Published material: Sos de Demon, Born, Amsterdam, 1970, Dutch translation; This item has been sent to Rare Books for cataloging. Please refer to to locate this item.
    - A Spell for Chameleon
      - 1st draft, holograph manuscript (Box 25)
      - 2nd draft, typescript manuscript (Box 26)
      - Final draft, typescript manuscript; 2 folders (Box 26)
    - Steppe, holograph manuscript, research notes, typescript manuscript; 3 folders (Box 26)
    - Tournament (Judo Story #4) (with Roberto Fuentes) (Box 27)
      Includes holograph and typescript manuscripts, with a good deal of back-and-forth correspondence with Roberto Fuentes. Although there is no book published with this title in Anthony's oeuvre, this is clearly part of the Jason Striker series of books (also known as "the Ninja books" or "the Judo books"), and has passages that appear in Kiai!
    - Triple Detente [working title: A Piece of Cake]
      - [Unidentified draft], holograph manuscript (Box 27)
      - "2nd draft", typescript manuscript (Box 27)
      - [Final draft], typescript manuscript (Box 27)
    - The Unstilled World, typescript manuscript, notes; includes a letter of critique from James Hotaling who had "Battle" as the title; this novel may have never been sold according to some sources; 3 folders (Box 27)
    - Var the Stick, 1969
      - Summary and 1st draft, holograph manuscript (Box 27)
      - "Second draft", typescript manuscript (Box 28)
      - Final draft manuscript, "galley proof", production records (Box 28)
  - Magazines
    - Science Fiction Review, no's 28-33 and 35, 1969; 2 folders (Box 28)
  - Poetry
    - Strange is the measure, holograph and typescript manuscript (Box 28)
    - Miscellaneous, holograph and typescript manuscript (Box 28)
  - School papers
    - Miscellaneous, 1951-1964 (Box 28)
  - Short stories
    - Anonymous Letter, holograph and typescript manuscript (Box 28)
    - Babble, written as a column for the fanzine BeABohema edited by Frank Lunney; typescript manuscript (Box 28)
    - Balook, holograph and typescript manuscript; also includes two additional stories, "Creator's Burden" by Rem and "E=m-oops!" by Andy with a critical letter analyzing each. (Box 28)
    - Bastille, typescript manuscript (Box 28)
    - Beak by Beak, notes, holograph draft manuscript, typescript manuscript, undated issue of Analog Science Fiction and Fact (Box 28)
    - Breath of Diplomacy, holograph and typescript manuscript (Box 28)
    - Buckwheat Jury, typescript manuscript (Box 29)
    - Business, holograph and typescript manuscript (Box 29)
    - Caterpillar, holograph and typescript manuscript (Box 29)
    - The Cloud, holograph and typescript manuscript (Box 29)
    - Country Man (writing as "Mat Temper"), typescript draft and manuscript (Box 29)
    - The Crabol!, typescript manuscript (Box 29)
    - Crystal, holograph manuscript, drafts, 2 typescript manuscripts (Box 29)
    - Dead Center, holograph, draft, and 2 typescript manuscripts (Box 29)
    - The Demise, 1958-1960; 2 typescript manuscripts (Box 29)
    - Deva, 4 typescript manuscripts, issue of Once Beyond the Time (1963) in which the story appears (Box 29)
    - Electrolous, holograph, draft, "1st carbon", "2nd carbon," and typescript manuscript (Box 29)
    - Encounter, notes, 2 drafts, typescript manuscript (Box 29)
    - Equals Four, holograph 1st draft, 2 "2nd drafts", and typescript manuscript (Box 29)
    - E van S, notes, holograph and draft manuscript, typescript manuscript for submission to the NFFF story contest, and a retyped manuscript of the contest story (Box 29)
    - "Evening", written while student at Goddard College; typescript manuscript (Box 29)
    - The Facsimile, typescript manuscript (Box 29)
    - Firebrand, typescript manuscript (Box 29)
    - Five Billion?, holograph and typescript manuscript (Box 29)
    - Frustration, draft and typescript manuscript (Box 29)
    - Ghost, notes, holograph manuscript; 4 drafts and typescript manuscript; 5 folders (Box 29)
    - Hearts, holograph, draft and typescript manuscript (Box 29)
    - Hot Pepper, typescript draft and 2 typescript manuscript (Box 29)
    - How Many Worlds, How Many Times (with Norbert Laus, Seth Johnson, Harvey Forman, and James Toren), typescript manuscript (Box 29)
    - In the Barn, notes, 1st draft holograph, 2nd draft typescript manuscript, 4 typescript copies, some of which have "The Barn" used as a title and one which is marked for revisions per Harlan Ellison's suggestions; two form letters from Harlan Ellison to the contributors to his Dangerous Visions anthology; unpublished at time of donation but appears in a later anthology of Anthony's short stories (Box 29)
    - In the Jaws of Danger [original title: The value of a man], typescript manuscript (Box 29)
    - Kylo, holograph and 3 typescript manuscripts (Box 30)
    - The Life of the Strip, holograph draft and typescript manuscript (Box 30)
    - Lost, 2 drafts and 1 typescript manuscript (Box 30)
    - The Message (with Frances Hall), notes, holograph manuscript, drafts, typescript manuscript; also includes manuscript entitled "Message to Acrux" with Ivy Hale as co-writer; 9 folders (Box 30)
    - Minnie's Crew, notes; holograph, draft, and typescript manuscript (Box 30)
    - Minority Speaker, typescript manuscript (Box 30)
    - Monarch, holograph, 2nd draft typescript and typescript manuscript (Box 30)
    - The Monster, 2 typescript manuscripts; includes letter from Thomas H. Uzzell (Box 30)
    - "Monster Tracks", Anthony's revision of a Robert Margroff story; typescript manuscript (Box 30)
    - None But I, notes, 1st draft holograph ms, "2nd draft" typescript manuscript, 1st carbon typescript manuscript, 2nd carbon typescript manuscript (Box 30)
    - On Being... (with D.L. Oppenheim), various draft revisions, 2 typescript manuscripts (Box 30)
    - Orn, holograph and typescript manuscript (Box 30)
    - Painted Lips, 4 typescript manuscripts (Box 30)
    - The Payoff (with Robert E. Margroff), typescript drafts; 10 folders (Box 30)
    - Penal Code (with Norbert Laus), notes, drafts, and typescript manuscript (Box 30)
    - Phog, notes, 1st draft, 2nd draft, typescript manuscript; includes issue of Fantastic, June 1965, v.14. no. 6 in which the story appears (Box 30)
    - Possible to Rue, 2 typescript manuscripts (Box 30)
    - Postscript, key, holograph and typescript manuscript (Box 30)
    - Prostho Plus [original title: "The Dillingham Manuscript"], notes, holograph and typescript draft ms, and 3 typescript manuscripts (Box 30)
    - P.S.I. (with Andrew J. Offutt), typescript manuscript (Box 30)
    - Quinquepedalian, notes, drafts and typescript manuscript; 8 folders (Box 31)
    - Red Thrill, typescript manuscript; also includes "The Rape of the Ring", revision draft of a story with author given as Robert Piers but probably by Robert E. Margroff (Box 31)
      See also The Ring (with Robert Margroff).
    - Revise and Invent, notes, holograph and typescript draft, 2 typescript manuscript (Box 31)
    - The Ring (with Robert Margroff), notes, holograph and draft; 2 typescript manuscripts; longer version (11,400 words) retitled "The Rape of the Ring" (Box 31)
      See also Red Thrill.
    - Root [alternate title: The Route], notes, holograph, preliminary copy, "1st typing", "2nd typing", typescript manuscript (Box 31)
    - Sheol 1964, undated, notes, drafts, issue of Analog v.74, no. 1 (Sept. 1964) which also includes "The Postman Never Rings" by H. James Hotaling and "Government Island," suggested by Anthony (Box 31)
    - Ship of Mustard, holograph, multiple draft and revised manuscript, and typescript manuscript (Box 31)
    - Six Vignettes, notes, typescript manuscript, Stopthink fanzine #1 and #2, circa 1964, containing two of the vignettes (Box 31)
    - The Skeleton of the Leaf, notes, holograph, drafts and revisions, typescript manuscript (Box 31)
    - Small Mouth, Bad Taste, holograph 1st draft, "2nd draft" typescript, and typescript manuscript (Box 31)